ABDULLAH AL MARUF

Software Engineer

Passionate software engineer with 2 years of working experience developing Kubernetes tools in GO. Acted as AppsCode's KubeDB project head for more than a year. Love to participate in programming contests. An enthusiastic team player.

maruf.2hin@gmail.com
+8801722777603

Dhaka, Bangladesh
https://maruftuhin.com
github.com/the-redback

linkedin.com/in/maruftuhin in

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer *AppsCode Ltd.* ✓

May, 2017 – Present

Dhaka Rangladesh

Subsidiary company of AppsCode Inc. USA. An Integrated platform for collaborative coding, testing & deploying containerized apps.

- Worked on Kubernetes client-GO to build third party containerized tools.
- Worked on KubeDB tool. Conducted Bi-Weekly KubeDB Community meetings regularly. Acted as KubeDB project head for more than a year. Got involved in other projects too.
- Worked on Pixel Tracking [web beacon], different APIs of mainstream cloud providers, etc.
- Created and used Kubernetes cluster on all the mainstream cloud providers, like, aws, gcs, azure, digitalocean etc. Also, experienced many Kubernetes tools.
- Worked with gRPC, Phabricator, Prometheus etc.

Intern

AppsCode Ltd.

1st January, 2016 – 15th January, 2016

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- 2 weeks long internship program.
- Implemented an Email verification tool in Java.
- Used Elasticsearch for data store purpose.

PROJECTS

KubeDB 2

- A tool to automate database deploy on *Kubernetes* using *CRD*. It also takes scheduled backup of databases.
- Added MongoDB, MySQL, Redis and Memcached support to KubeDB.
- Added MongoDB clustering system. Also, worked on PostgreSQL and Elasticsearch clustering.
- Worked with prometheus exporter to export database metrics.

Appscode/Analytics 🗷

- Worked with docker-hub APIs to collect analytic data and stored them in Google sheets using GO client.
- Used pixel tracking [aka, web beacon] to event each view of GitHub or other web pages in real time.

3D Racing Game 🗷

- Final year thesis & project.
- Developed for both PC and Android.
- Tools: Unity 5 Game Engine, Android SDK, C#.

Academic Projects

- ▶ Department of Student Welfare (DSW) Management System using C# and MySQL.
- Library Management System using C# and Microsoft SQL Server.
- Scientific Calculator using Java swing.
- Automatic Email Verification using Java as Internship Project.
- Data encryption project in Java. <a>C

TECHNICAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

BSc. in Computer Science & EngineeringChittagong University of Engineering & Technology

Session: 2011-12

Chittagong, Bangladesh

ACHIEVEMENTS

Competitive Programming (June, 2012 - Present)

- Solved overall 900+ problems on different Online Judges.
- Participated many onsite programming contests with team name CUET-One_1.
- Became divisional champion in 2 ICPC Dhaka Regional (ICPC-2014 & ICPC-2015) with varsity rank 7th and 8th
- Got 6th position at national level IUPC-2016 at SUB.
- Got 1st position at regional IUPC-2015 at USTC and also performed well in other national and divisional contests.

Open Source Contribution (May, 2017 - Present)

Contributed on open source projects including Kubernetes, KubeDB, appscode/osm, appscode/kutil, appscode/analytics etc.

Extra Curriculum

- Former **President** of **CUET Computer Club**.
- Former member of CUET Debating Society.
- Organizer of CUET CSE FEST 2015 and CUET NCPC 2017.
- Provided problem set in several IUPC.
- > Attended many self-developing training courses.

STRENGTHS

Team Work	• • • • •
Optimist	
Communication	
Problem Solving	
Self Learning	
Tech Savvy	

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Competitive Programming History Traveling

Gaming Photography